Solomon Obúre

Email: solo.obure@gmail.com | Phone: 331 999 0144 | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/solomonobure/

Git: github.com/sobure

Software Engineer with 4 years of full stack experience in MERN stacks and ERP environments. Good understanding of cloud computing principles and certifications in AWS. Collaborator on complex system integrations using various types of APIs and databases in addition to implementing current industry front end technologies.

Strong problem solving abilities in debugging and capable of taking on large problems and breaking them into smaller ones. Comfortable communicating with clients, scoping project requirements, and asking the right questions.

Currently open to positions that are in-person, hybrid, or remote. Able to relocate if needed.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Typescript| JavaScript| HTML|CSS| React| Node| Express| NoSQL| MySQL| MongoDB| Firebase| JSON|REST API| SOAP API| Command Line| Unit Testing| AWS| GIT| Versioning| NetSuite| Celigo | Liquid | Shopify | Java | .NET2222

PROJECTS:

Wander June 2020-June 2021

Web App - JavaScript - ReactJS - MongoDB - Firebase - NodeJS - Heroku

- Geosocial Networking application allowing users to discover other traveling companions
- Users discovers travelers pinned to cities on the Google Maps React UI
- Developed using a MERN Stack
- Authentication provided via Firebase Authentication
- As a Backend Developer, I worked on developing database relationships, creating backend-routes,
 utilizing react states and managing the routing of secure user data
- As a Frontend Developer, I wireframed accessible responsive layouts using Figma, developed React components using Material UI

 As a Co-Project Manager, I applied an agile process to ensure daily objectives were outlined, deliverable, and received. Responsible for versioning through creating, reviewing, and deploying branches

DishTracker

June 2020-December 2021

Web App - JavaScript - REST Api - Jquery - Ajax - Express - Github Pages

- An information service application that allows users to save local menu items from favorite restaurants
- As a Back End Developer, I worked on creating routes, making api calls and parsing returned data accordingly
- As a Front End Developer, I created the landing page using Figma and ensuring accessibility
- As a Project Manager, I applied an agile process to ensure daily objectives were outlined, deliverable and received. Responsible for versioning through creating, reviewing, and deploying branches

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS:

University of Georgia Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering
University of Minnesota Full Stack Web Development Professional Cert.

Amazon AWS June 2021 Amazon Certified Cloud Practitioner Certification

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Soco Dzn.

Aug 2019 - Current Minneapolis, Minnesota - Remote

Javascript Developer

- Founded a consulting firm focused on product development, digital media, brand strategy, and brand standards
- Managing a team of interns with ranging backgrounds in Computer Science, Marketing, Art, and Journalism
- Designed and implemented e-commerce stores for customers grossing over \$100,000 in sales
- Increased social media engagements by 127% for clients by using automation tools

BerganKDV

September 2021 - June 2023 Bloomington, Minnesota - Remote

Javascript Developer

- Responsible for architecting and developing custom NetSuite solutions using SuiteScript, SQL databases, vendor APIs, and integration platforms such as Celigo
- Maintained integrations for internal systems that utilized SOAP, REST, and XML web services
- Designed UI interfaces and templates using HTML, CSS, TypeScript and FreeMarker
- Utilized best practices in managing environments, versioning, and deployment

UPS

May 2019 - September 2019 Atlanta, Georgia

Controls Engineer Supervisor

- Responsible for cross functional systems such as CCD cameras, laser scanners, programmable logic controls, and embedded control devices communicated using system protocols(e.g., TCP/IP, UDP IP, HTTP, MODBUS, etc)
- Supervised a fast paced control room which required communicating with different departments, task delegation, and commanding the Human Machine Interface
- Analyzed statistical data using data software to determine machine efficiencies and process improvements to implement
- Created reports of sort performance, occurring breakdowns and proper corrective actions on worn down equipment

Hansen Technologies

January 2018 - January 2019 Commerce, Georgia

Engineer I

- Designed and commercialized industrial refrigeration products adhering to strict ISO and national boards standards
- Responsible for validation testing of experiments, testing protocols, and product specifications
- Reported daily status of tasks such as ideation, research, testing, and patent documentation as part of new product development team while working with vendors to develop concept prototypes
- Drafted dimensioned prints for fixtures and tools using SOLIDWORKS and Auto-CAD
- Employed statistical and data analysis software such as Minitab, Rapidminer, and Matlab to investigate root cause of quality issues
- Developed and executed testing procedures for new product development